Rajan Mani Tripathi

Student

To purse a challenging career and be part of a progressive organization that gives scope to enhance my knowledge, skills and to reach the pinnacle in the computing and research field with sheer determination, dedication and hard work.



rajanmanitripathi99@gmail.c



8374970567



Hyderabad, India



linkedin.com/in/rajan-manitripathi



github.com/RajanKing

SKILLS

Python3

Java8





Machine Learning

Android Development



CSS

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Telugu

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Programming

Research

Travelling

Machine Learning

Data Science

Deep Learning

Robotics

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

Malla Reddy Institute of Engineering and Technology

06/2017 - 09/2021 Hyderabad

Intermediate

Gautami Academy Jr.College

06/2015 - 06/2017

S.R.Nagar

Hyderabad

WORK EXPERIENCE

Question Paper Analyzer

As an Intent in Stem Innovation Technologies

06/2019 - 06/2019

Analysis of Duplication Question Paper in pdf Solutions

Front End: Tkinter BackEnd: MySql

Using PIL and pdf2image module of python analyses pdf and converting into text .Then using pytestract to analyses of text on taken images text. Storing the data in database if no duplication found

Engineering IntenNPrime

04/2021 - 09/2021 Hyderabad

NPRIME provides solutions for Biometric identification and verification systems using Fingerprint and Face.

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked On Face Identification, Mask Detection
- Created anti soofing model to identify fake or real face.
- Created android library to detect face mask

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Automatic Music creation (03/2021 - 05/2021)

- Created a Deep Learning neural network for analysis of music note and creating the preferred music from the given nodes.
- Learnt to work with different data and Handle lstm and rnn network model.

Digital Institute (12/2020 - 01/2021)

 Created a platform for student and faculty to interact with each other. It was develop as according to covid-19 sitution.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Finalist in Smart India Hackathon (06/2020 - 07/2020)

It was a excellent experience being a part of SIH

Top 9 rank in Red hat it Apptitude test

Finalist in Megathon IIITH (12/2019 - 12/2019)

It was fun learning about big data and working with micron probelm.